

Paul Daniel

Team Lead

□ pauldaniel1991@gmail.com □ +91-9789030524

Handling Team with over 6+ years of experience in managing 20+ resources totally 100+ members are trained in carrier and 10+ projects successfully completed in HTC-ITES department. Excellent track record of handling projects, with an average rating of 4.3/5 over the past 6 years.

Experience

Team Lead

HTC Global Services, Chennai | Feb 2014 to Mar 2021

- Planned, scheduled and delegated daily work to team of employees.
- Generated and perpetuated daily, weekly and monthly reports.
- Projected **pivot reports** and **charts** for productivity and quality trends visually through email.
- Fitch and Extract reports from Sql database for data Analysis
- Analyze data using MS Excel to validate an accuracy of the report
- Evaluated team by Ensuring the report numbers.
- Tracked daily production and inventory usage to support operational planning and strategic decision making.
- Manipulated various operations and email support factors regularly.
- Responsible for **client deliver's** and project reports.

Vendor Team Coordinator

HTC Global Services, Chennai | Oct 2020 to Mar 2021

- Administered to send and receive instruction documents and all 5+ project files.
- Handled 5+ projects and 8 vendor companies for my company project requirement.
- Thoughtful to break down problems, evaluate solutions and make decisions efficiently.
- Generate reports using SQL database tools for various server's
- Delivered quality and productivity feedback to enhance vendor performance on a regular basis through calls and zoom meetings to reach grater 95% accuracy.
- Developed and maintained courteous and effective working relationship with vendor organizations.

Education

- Data Science Using Python
 IIT Madras Guvi | Chennai | May 2021 to Dec 2021
- **B.E. Electrical and Electronics Engineering**Vi Institute of Technology | Chennai | Sep 2009 to May 2013

Technical Skills

- Advanced MS Excel (6y+ Exp)
- SQL (3y+ Exp)
- Python (1+ year)
- Power BI (1 year)
- Mango DB (8 months)
- Machine Learning & AI (10m)
- AWS
- Tableau

General Skills

- Multi-Tasking
- Data Visualization
- Statical Analysis
- Data Analytics
- Workflow Analysis
- Project Management
- Strong decision maker

Certification

- Power BI
- Business Analytics with Excel
- Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Language

- English
- Tamil